# **Zach Kerner**

# Software Engineer

■ zachkernerdev@gmail.com

 New York, New York

 ★ zachkerner.dev

 □ zachkerner

#### **PROFILE**

I'm a full stack software engineer with extensive experience in JavaScript and Ruby. I'm proficient in Go, TypeScript and the AWS cloud infrastructure. I'm a culture builder with a talent for reading people, which enables me to collaborate successfully with a wide range of personalities.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer2023 – presentMayfly ∅2023 – present

- Developed a multi-tier architecture for the automated deployment of containerized applications as running instances made accessible through endpoint URLs. (Docker, AWS EC2, AMI, EBS, Lambda, AWSCLI)
- Resolved a longstanding bug in the internal DNS that was blocking communication between drone and controller.
- Scaled the number of running drones from 1 to 20 which increased the number of concurrent connections to 10000.
- Reconstructed a database schema halving the number of round trips to the server. (**PostgreSQL**)
- Architected a RESTful API in **Node** and **Express** to enable communication between NATS, a pub/sub message queue, the database tier and 3rd party software.
- Designed a UI for streamlining user experience with **React** and Tailwind CSS.
- Authored an in-depth case study Ø that provides a comprehensive analysis of Mayfly's problem domain and use case.
- Collaborated remotely with a team of engineers using agile workflow.

Software Engineer 2021 – 2023

Self-employed

Developed freelance and open-source applications with a variety of languages and technologies.

- HasBin an application for pooling and debugging webhooks (DO Droplet, MongoDB, Node.js, Express, React, Nginx)
- *Pubs* an app for rated pickup basketball games (**Ruby**, **Heroku**, **Sinatra**, **PostgreSQL**)

## **SKILLS**

- Back End Node.js, Express, Ruby, Go, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, REST, APIs
- Front End JavaScript, React, TypeScript, HTML/CSS
- Cloud Digital Ocean, AWS (Lambda, EC2, EBS, ECS, CLI, SDK), Heroku
- Other Docker, GitHub, Bash, Linux, Nginx, OOP, Jest, Postman, Prompt Engineering

## **EDUCATION**

Launch School

Multi-year, mastery-based software engineering curriculum. Read more at launchschool.com/employers ∂

BA Math/BS Economics

Binghamton University

Shapell's Rabbinical College

Completed a rigorous curriculum in Talmud, Bible and other classical texts in the original Hebrew and Aramaic.

MA Middle Eastern Studies

2018 - 2020

Tel Aviv University